DOMINIC BISHOP

Portfolio

dominicbishop.com

Contact

Mobile number: 07768769821
Email: dmncbishop@gmail.com

Education

Fullstack Bootcamp

Team Treehouse, October 2019 - October 2020

2:1 BA (HONS)

Interior Architecture

Portsmouth University September 2015 - July 2018

PASS Level 4 Diploma

Art Foundation

South coast college September 2013 - July 2015

10 GCSE's, 3 A levels

GCSE & A levels

Uplands Community College September 2006 - July 2013

Software Skills

· Languages: Typescript, Python, PHP

• Fameworks: Angular, React, NestJS, Playwright, Laravel

· Dev ops: Docker,

Version control: Git,

• Cloud services: DigitalOcean, Auth0, AWS S3, Stripe

· Database: Postgres

General Skills

- · Impeccable organisational skills
- · Creative problem solver
- · High attention to detail
- · Excellent communicator
- · Strong work ethic
- Self-motivated

Profile

I am a detail-oriented professional with nearly 5 years of experience in software development, including almost three years in a commercial setting. I have a strong background in modern languages, frameworks, and technologies. With a keen eye for accuracy and a focus on continuous improvement, I excel in both independent and team-based environments, using my technical expertise to identify and resolve issues, drive testing efforts, and contribute to the success of quality assurance initiatives.

Experience

Junior Software Developer

Scaffoldbid

June 2023 - Present

- Contributed to the development of a robust testing suite using Playwright.
- Wrote a in house development tool to clean up test data in our platform staging environment and across multiple supporting services.
- Developed a feature so users can download assets from AWS S3 buckets while interacting with the UI.
- Implemented an admin panel tool to enable administrators to efficiently browse and manage user data.
- Applied our CircleCl version hashes to the backend via the Dockerfile and saved them locally using a bash script.
- Integrated a throttling feature into the platform to stop users from abusing asset downloads.
- Contributed to the development of Scaffoldbid using Nest.js, Angular, PostgreSQL and Docker.

Junior Web Developer

Net Natives

April 2022 - June 2023

- Developed custom JavaScript animations for advertisement banners using GSAP.
- Developed interactive quizzes with React, for enhancing the student experience.

AutoCAD Technician

RAD Fire Sprinklers

February 2019 - April 2022

- Worked in a large team drawing schematics for fire sprinkler systems using AutoCAD.
- Developed my skills liaising with clients, understanding their needs and wants to bring projects to a successful close.